The end begins.
Terminator Salvation is a action, science
fiction, thriller film directed by McG.
All grown up in post-apocalyptic 2018, John Connor must lead the resistance of
humans against the increasingly dominating militaristic robots.
But when Marcus Wright appears, his existence confuses the mission as Connor tries to determine
whether Wright has come from the future or the past -- and whether he's friend or foe.
John Connor, played by Christian Bale.
Marcus Wright, played by Sam Worthington.
Blair Williams, played by Moon Bloodgood.
Serena, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Kyle Reese, played by Anton Yelchin.
Barnes, played by Common.
Terminator Salvation is a 2009 American military science fiction action film.
It is the fourth installment of the Terminator franchise, serving as a
sequel to Terminator 3: Rise of the Machines (2003).
It is directed by McG and written by John Brancato and Michael Ferris.
It is the only Terminator film to date not to feature Arnold
Schwarzenegger, though his likeness briefly appears digitally.
Instead, it stars Christian Bale and Sam Worthington with Anton Yelchin, Moon Bloodgood, Bryce
Dallas Howard, Common, Michael Ironside, and Helena Bonham Carter in supporting roles.
In a departure from the previous installments, Salvation is a
post-apocalyptic film set in the year 2018.
It focuses on the war between Skynet's machine network and humanity, as the remnants of the
world's militaries have united to form the Resistance to fight against Skynet.
Bale portrays John Connor, a Resistance fighter and central
character, while Worthington portrays cyborg Marcus Wright.
Yelchin plays a young Kyle Reese, a character first introduced in The Terminator
(1984), and the film depicts the origins of the T-800 Terminator.
After troubled pre-production, with the Halcyon
Company acquiring the rights from Andrew G.
Vajna and Mario Kassar, and with several writers working on the screenplay,
filming began in May 2008 in New Mexico, and ran for 77 days.
Terminator Salvation was released on May 21, 2009, by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States, and by Sony Pictures Releasing under its Columbia Pictures label
internationally, and grossed over $371.4 million worldwide but received mixed-to-negative reviews.
While originally intended to be the first installment of a second Terminator trilogy, these plans were
canceled following the Halcyon Company filing for bankruptcy after the film's release.
The franchise rights were sold in 2012 to Annapurna Pictures, resulting in Terminator Genisys, a
reboot of the series, being released in 2015 with Schwarzenegger reprising his role.
The film explores themes of army, artificial intelligence (a.i.),
saving the world, prophecy, san francisco, california.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.